[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c488", "question": "Where is the tragus located on a human body?", "answer": "Near the ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078c480eee65b76b9f2671", "question": "What was the first modern credit card?", "answer": "Diners Club", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf94", "question": "What does an onychophagist do?", "answer": "Bite their nails", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af258dfb63e5727cf5a4849", "question": "Who sang the 1995 song \"Boom Boom Boom\"?", "answer": "The Outhere Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938f", "question": "What role did James Dean play in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "Jim Stark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c374", "question": "What common garden flowers are fed to chickens to give their skin an appealing golden color?", "answer": "Marigolds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c80d877e98cb977789dc", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Greece?", "answer": "Mount Olympus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e33", "question": "Who is Mia Farrow's mother?", "answer": "Maureen O'Sullivan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c3ce877e98cb97778997", "question": "Where are the Admiralty Islands?", "answer": "Papua New Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5e", "question": "What North American Soccer League team signed Pele in 1975?", "answer": "The New York Cosmos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb2", "question": "Which German city was the birthplace of the poet Heinrich Heine?", "answer": "Dusseldorf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab1b3234fda37788a9a1dc0", "question": "What is the basis for guacamole?", "answer": "Avocado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339423", "question": "What basketball player starred alongside Jean Claude Van Damme in the movie \"Double Team\"?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8e", "question": "What is the practical purpose of the Pharos of Alexandria?", "answer": "Lighthouse", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24b", "question": "What is the name of Bryan Adams' third studio album, released in 1983?", "answer": "Cuts Like a Knife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c1", "question": "Who is the world's richest duck?", "answer": "Scrooge McDuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b4afe662d71a53650fee", "question": "What Edgar Allan Poe work launched his writing career?", "answer": "\"The Raven\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba35c874c93a3298b213a", "question": "A Polyorchid has at least three what?", "answer": "Testicles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc81aec223966ae8f888e", "question": "What is the name of the spider that paralyzes Frodo in the film \"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Shelob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049903cf93664eb104868d", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Tennessee?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c862", "question": "What's the common name for the foot ailment also called verrucas?", "answer": "Plantar warts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0dc", "question": "\"Little Bastard\" was the nickname given to the Porsche 550 Spyder that killed what acting icon in a crash?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f7405cb9e8bda682136e", "question": "What year was the wreck of the Titanic discovered?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfa", "question": "What was the name of King Arthur's sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45d", "question": "The island country Grenada is also known as what?", "answer": "Island of Spice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a639", "question": "What animal is depicted on the flag of California?", "answer": "Grizzly Bear", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b351", "question": "Which US President was the first to have an indoor Christmas tree in the White House?", "answer": "Benjamin Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a3dfcf93664eb10486c0", "question": "Not including spin-offs or tie-ins, how many issues were released as part of the original \"Strangers in Paradise\" series that ended in 2007?", "answer": "90", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936e", "question": "Which actor appears in both the 1968 and 1999 versions of the movie \"The Thomas Crown Affair\"?", "answer": "Faye Dunaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaed190738315b1fb74e2e", "question": "In what year did the first president of Kenya die?", "answer": "1978", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a1b620565ad31a57c7a5", "question": "What was the first US state to have two female senators at the same time?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6be", "question": "What bird has the largest beak relative to its body size?", "answer": "The Toucan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae48", "question": "When was the Emancipation Proclamation enacted?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2de", "question": "What year did actor Stan Laurel die?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c475", "question": "Herman Hollerith was known for what contribution to society?", "answer": "Punch card accounting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babc", "question": "What space lies between Baltic Avenue and Reading Railroad on a standard Monopoly game board?", "answer": "Income Tax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71b", "question": "What word describes a horse with a golden coat and a white or silver mane and tail?", "answer": "Palomino", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a162c2ef01ec323f849172e", "question": "Who was the legendary front man for the band Roxy Music?", "answer": "Bryan Ferry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76c92eec85e375820b2d4", "question": "The ruins of the ancient city of Ephesus are located in what present day country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4c", "question": "How many syllables are there in Japanese haiku?", "answer": "Seventeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e19a06d333868d34d728", "question": "How long was Francisco Franco in power in Spain?", "answer": "36 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2a", "question": "In the US Army, what four ranks lie between First Lieutenant and Brigadier General?", "answer": "Captain, Major, Lieutenant Colonel and Colonel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a8", "question": "What was the name of Alexander the Great's famous horse?", "answer": "Bucephalas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf20", "question": "What does barley become when prepared for brewing?", "answer": "Malt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccc2bec223966ae8f88a2", "question": "What was the name of Rocky Balboa's dog?", "answer": "Butkus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec4d08d98002fdd633ba", "question": "Which character, that first appeared in the book \"Winnie-the-Pooh\", loves watercress?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071fe43745b36be73039ed", "question": "What does an Advent calendar count down to?", "answer": "Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b759", "question": "The two-cent piece was the first US coin to feature which phrase?", "answer": "In God We Trust", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cdcd7bd84c0ea43ad42f", "question": "Skopje is the capital of which Eastern European country?", "answer": "Macedonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aabe", "question": "What are the three colors of the flag of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Red, White and Blue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbbb", "question": "On what date did the \"Dennis the Menace\" comic strip debut in newspapers?", "answer": "March 12, 1951", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd4", "question": "Baklava is usually made using what kind of paper-thin dough?", "answer": "Filo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a959d61d1b4d384d5d67b", "question": "\"White Room\" was a hit off which Cream album?", "answer": "Wheels of Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd5f8a0499cffc60b84236", "question": "Who was the founder of the Mongol Empire?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c523877e98cb977789ab", "question": "Which island was once named the \"Island of the Pelicans\"?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015eac4fe83fe1f2a824bf4", "question": "What does the color white represent in the American flag?", "answer": "White symbolizes purity and innocence.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab88", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c308", "question": "How long is the giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "17 inches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ccf7d86b37b32637bdc44cc", "question": "Monet and Van Gogh are two examples of late 19th century artists who painted in a style called?", "answer": "Impressionism", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6cb", "question": "Which US state is home to Lassen Volcano National Park?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe937d26bd93ce3a4e5f678", "question": "Glossophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Public speaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88a", "question": "In which decade was the first aluminum bat used in professional baseball?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a203", "question": "What was Lucille Ball's Broadway stage name?", "answer": "Diane Belmont and Dianne Belmont", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970d", "question": "Actor Jason Lee was a professional in which sport?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff2", "question": "What is the principle ingredient of the dish Biryani?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c4", "question": "Who played the role of Honey Rider in the first James Bond movie?", "answer": "Ursula Andress", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21c", "question": "What city was Wild Bill Hickok killed in?", "answer": "Deadwood", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf71", "question": "What product was originally manufactured by communications giant Nokia?", "answer": "Paper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933b", "question": "On the TV show \"South Park\", which character wears a blue hat with a red pom-pom on it?", "answer": "Stan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338992", "question": "How old is the teenage lead character at the end of the book \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be04", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b16f", "question": "What architect was responsible for the design of the Brooklyn Bridge?", "answer": "John Augustus Roebling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c912", "question": "What is sulphur also known as?", "answer": "Brimstone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be580815415ba52ed6f0ab5", "question": "Approximately, how many seconds comprise a day?", "answer": "86400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb3d965ff7d326b622a80", "question": "What century saw the War of the Roses?", "answer": "The 15th century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff7", "question": "What do you call filo pastry stuffed with chopped nuts and honey, or syrup?", "answer": "Baklava", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b326", "question": "Who was the wife of King Ahab?", "answer": "Jezebel of Sidon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f4", "question": "How many claws does a housecat have?", "answer": "Eighteen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad08", "question": "What H-word means designing, displaying and describing coats of arms and badges?", "answer": "Heraldry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fbaefe83fe1f2a824c3b", "question": "Some Irish old stories suggest that St. Patrick's walking stick once miraculously tranformed into what object?", "answer": "There are stories that say he stuck his ash walking stick in the ground that he wanted to evangelize. It grew into a tree.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d470b0f8e329de4f877894", "question": "Who was the NBA's most valuable player in 1976, 1977 and 1980?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65f211f3c0ead6880d635", "question": "Which President of South Africa ordered Nelson Mandela\u2019s release from prison?", "answer": "De Klerk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b746", "question": "The serial killer Larry Eyler was also known as what?", "answer": "The Highway Killer/The Interstate Killer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8c8aec223966ae8f884c", "question": "Which famous Christmas movie is based on the story of a boy outsmarting a couple of adult thieves?", "answer": "\"Home Alone\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2c", "question": "Which is the largest lake by area in the British Isles?", "answer": "Lough Neagh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b3", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan became famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd0", "question": "In what city was the Wright brothers' bicycle shop?", "answer": "Dayton, Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65c911f3c0ead6880d616", "question": "What natural occurrence was said to have helped the British navy defeat the Spanish Armada in 1588?", "answer": "A Protestant Wind", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72cce8d0874f1a5e2d1c25", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32363fbf195a31e15d73b9", "question": "In which of Coleridge's poems does an albatross appear?", "answer": "Rime of the Ancient Mariner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cc", "question": "What is the official name for the \"pound\" or \"number\" symbol on the telephone keypad?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b239", "question": "What royal subject married Grace Kelly?", "answer": "Rainier III of Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54d", "question": "What is the complementary colour of red?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ed", "question": "How many pounds did Johnny Depp have to lose for the role of Edward Scissorhands?", "answer": "25", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd1", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"H\"?", "answer": "Hotel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fd", "question": "Which continent was host to the 1992 Summer and Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f83", "question": "Who is associated with the address 221B Baker Street, London?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3e", "question": "According to legend, who cut the tree-bark rope tied into a \"Gordian knot\"?", "answer": "Alexander the Great", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efb", "question": "What movie is available in the \"Don't Call Me Shirley!\" DVD edition?", "answer": "Airplane!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9e", "question": "What is the capital of Uzbekistan?", "answer": "Tashkent", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ee0b08d98002fdd633d0", "question": "What is the fear of beards called?", "answer": "Pogonophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bea", "question": "In which Verdi opera does Violetta die in the arms of Alfredo?", "answer": "La Traviata", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078481bd51d85e222ab65b", "question": "Who said, \"A dog has the soul of a philosopher\"?", "answer": "Plato (The Greek philosopher believed the soul consisted of three parts - reason, spirit and appetite.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a31", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1962 award-winning film \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "Peter O\u2019Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a778", "question": "What former Soviet Republic lies just across the Gulf of Finland from Finland?", "answer": "Estonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d6f82596a59cbdfbd3b0", "question": "Who invented the lint roller?", "answer": "Nicholas McKay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca71", "question": "What term is applied to animals or plants that are not nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1de", "question": "Which US president lived in Mount Vernon?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b7", "question": "What nationality is actor Stephen Fry?", "answer": "British", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51c", "question": "What deadly disease is also known a hydrophobia?", "answer": "Rabies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323622bf195a31e15d73b7", "question": "What year was the character of Betty Crocker first introduced?", "answer": "1921", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab44", "question": "Vienna is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b8", "question": "Which character did Tom Hanks play in the movie \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Robert Langdon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d5", "question": "In 1991, who finally broke Bob Beamon's decades-old long jump record?", "answer": "Mike Powell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c1fd4f032c0db195b47c", "question": "What war lasted approximately 38 minutes?", "answer": "The\u00a0Anglo-Zanzibar War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edd", "question": "What position was first held by John Adams?", "answer": "US Vice President", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9503574a5ce6b56b824f", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf56", "question": "Which type of prepared bread is named after an opera singer?\u00a0", "answer": "Melba Toast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0e62596a59cbdfbd383", "question": "Which country was the first to enact daylight savings time?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1c", "question": "What German composer wrote \"Ode to Joy\"?", "answer": "Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e024fe83fe1f2a824b87", "question": "Who organized the famous \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Theodore Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9f", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Mars Attacks!\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a5cb90aac110e4167076", "question": "In the beer industry, what does the abbreviation O.G. stand for?", "answer": "Original gravity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ab", "question": "Which US President was responsible for the \"Louisiana Purchase\"?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926e", "question": "How tall is the Academy Award statue?", "answer": "13.5 inches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de0", "question": "What former musician played bass on Madonna's \"Like a Prayer\"?", "answer": "Randy Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d7522596a59cbdfbd3b4", "question": "Who gave the famous speech, \"Give me liberty or give me death\"?", "answer": "Patrick Henry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afcc", "question": "What fort was built on Garden Key in the Dry Tortugas islands?", "answer": "Fort Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede60a6ce05a3942286df4", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc2", "question": "What is the last name of the \"Evil Dead\" series protagonist Ash?", "answer": "Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37c", "question": "What city would one find the Louvre in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22e", "question": "What brainchild of Wisconsin senator Gaylord Nelson was first celebrated on April 22, 1970?", "answer": "Earth Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b371e31c3f17ccc40c8e20", "question": "What country is home to the longest street in the world?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3fb", "question": "Who was the 20th President of the US?", "answer": "James Garfield", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8f", "question": "In which US state was President Bill Clinton born?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133badd", "question": "What country won the men\u2019s World Cup in soccer in 2010?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c051", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Finland?", "answer": "Whooper swan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76f3eeec85e375820b2e5", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a2106c0f9723ab15cb3e", "question": "How many constellations are there in the sky?", "answer": "48 traditional Western constellations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29e", "question": "What fraction pure is 18-carat gold?", "answer": "Three-quarters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d71e2596a59cbdfbd3b2", "question": "What was the original name of the Popsicle?", "answer": "Eppsicle (Eppsicle was named after its creator, Frank Epperson.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b8", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Maurice \"Rocket\" Richard born?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c2", "question": "Which son of Hypnos was the god of dreams?", "answer": "Morpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99f", "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the Earth's moon?", "answer": "Tides", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4c", "question": "What sign are you if you were born on Valentine\u2019s Day?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fb", "question": "The Bitterroot Range of the Rockies is located on the border between what two US states?", "answer": "Idaho and Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58c", "question": "What interstate highway connects Boston and Seattle?", "answer": "I-90", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523dfa736d4be723796b49", "question": "What does the \"Calgary Stampede\" bills itself as?", "answer": "The Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900e", "question": "What was Tom Clancy's blockbuster first novel, published in 1984?", "answer": "The Hunt for Red October", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f3", "question": "What type of food is Lollo Rosso?", "answer": "Lettuce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16a", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Day of the Jackal\"?", "answer": "Fred Zinnemann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a9", "question": "What traditional Russian instrument looks like a triangular guitar?", "answer": "The balalaika", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a834", "question": "Which two countries does The Netherlands border?", "answer": "Belgium and Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a180cad1ec93f27df777", "question": "What are the main ingredients in a Cafe Cubano?", "answer": "Espresso and demerara sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c320", "question": "What kind of creature is a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "A Marsupial", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7a", "question": "What novel won John Steinbeck a Pulitzer Prize in 1940?", "answer": "Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cade", "question": "For which viral disease did Louis Pasteur develop a vaccine?", "answer": "Rabies\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ec", "question": "What is the standard tuning of a guitar?", "answer": "E A D G B E", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ee0606d333868d34d772", "question": "Where can you find the world\u2019s longest-operating \"Santa School\"?", "answer": "Midland, Michigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b59501dd7bf43be5e7d2", "question": "What was Big Ben renamed to in 2012?", "answer": "Elizabeth Tower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e088fe83fe1f2a824b8f", "question": "What was the highest denomination bill ever printed in the United States?", "answer": "$100,000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c7", "question": "The resort city of Aspen is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ce", "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Massachusetts?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d3", "question": "In which country was the singer Mika born?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25e", "question": "In what apartment complex was Rose Mary Woods living in the early 1970s?", "answer": "The Watergate", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5c", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Florida?", "answer": "Tallahassee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9dac7e748bb36357acdd5", "question": "What is the largest fish living today?", "answer": "The Whale shark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec4", "question": "What make is the missing vehicle in the movie \"Dude, Where's My Car\"?", "answer": "Renault", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e93a9d2d6f11f394a3b2d5d", "question": "How many apples can you put in an empty box?", "answer": "1, after that it is not empty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee6", "question": "What two colors make the color green?", "answer": "Blue and yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14621b0ee8c595b6d39bf", "question": "Which classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071c8a3745b36be73039cd", "question": "What is the name of the first space launch facility?", "answer": "Baikonur Cosmodrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22b", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1979 film \"Mad Max\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2c", "question": "How many balls are on a pool table at the start of a game?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a373", "question": "What is the capital of Germany?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b96", "question": "What was the first book Margaret Mitchell wrote?", "answer": "Gone With The Wind", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002433f4be4723ccac22193", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Russian-American author Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5f", "question": "Prague is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b8b701dd7bf43be5e7ed", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "A lounge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd820ecd0de9af39e9d46a0", "question": "What state is home to US' oldest newspaper still being printed?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52c5c1bf59ab7d2e38108", "question": "What was the top-selling vehicle in the United States in 2017?", "answer": "Ford F-Series", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c984", "question": "What is the collective term for ducks?", "answer": "A paddle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac41", "question": "What was The City of Gold sought by Spanish explorers?", "answer": "El Dorado", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339368", "question": "In the 1960 movie \"Psycho\", what actor plays the private detective?", "answer": "Martin Balsam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae860a84007905755f79e8f", "question": "What year was Julius Caeser assassinated", "answer": "44 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8beeec223966ae8f8845", "question": "The protagonist in \"Grand Theft Auto: Vice City\" was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e1", "question": "What river separates Maryland and Virginia?", "answer": "Potomac River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338934", "question": "Approximately how many lines is \"Beowulf\", the longest Old English manuscript?", "answer": "Over 3,000", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53c", "question": "What is the largest muscle in the human body?", "answer": "Gluteus Maximus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ef2108d98002fdd633de", "question": "When is the only time a flag should be flown upside down?", "answer": "Emergency", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa2", "question": "Which tax was introduced into Britain in 1973?", "answer": "VAT", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b267", "question": "What empress gave John Paul Jones a navy job after his American military career ended?", "answer": "Catherine the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d99a508b8581f80b092b6", "question": "What highly awaited Japanese hot hatchback went on sale around the world in 2017?", "answer": "Honda Civic Type R", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa40edc73aa70ea0b70b0c", "question": "What does the shape of Nepal's flag represent?", "answer": "The Himalayas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20ff931a458464a93c43a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bc", "question": "Which beverage was promoted during the 1990s by three frogs croaking out its name?", "answer": "Budweiser", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7bcbc2b316f4693fb678c", "question": "A kirby-grip is the British name for what hair accessory?", "answer": "Bobby pin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69d4b20565ad31a57c777", "question": "Robert E. Lee and Ulysses S. Grant both owned horses with what name?", "answer": "Jeff Davis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab39", "question": "Belgrade lies on the Danube and which other river?", "answer": "Sava", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f01", "question": "Whose \"Adagio for Strings\" is best known as the theme from the movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Samuel Barber's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8b", "question": "What former World Heavyweight Champion boxer was nicknamed \"The Brown Bomber\"?", "answer": "Joe Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bb", "question": "Which four US states share a border with Texas?", "answer": "Arkansas, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7decff048f679a45ac02", "question": "Aphenphosmphobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Being touched", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f4c4fa5fdd6dd25324e5", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the north?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff141fab0ee8c595b6d39a9", "question": "What color was Anna Karenina's bag in the Tolstoy novel of the same name?", "answer": "Red", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010cb030775fa611bce6801", "question": "What is the name of a word that is spelled the same forwards and backward?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa5ad73838c5c8a417f29", "question": "What do speleologists study?", "answer": "Wild cave systems", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e539fe83fe1f2a824bba", "question": "Which god is considered the \"destroyer\" and is part of the Hindu Trinity?", "answer": "Shiva", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e147743dd42e4a67cb8d3e9", "question": "Which Star Trek film features both Captain Kirk and Captain Picard?", "answer": "Star Trek : Generations", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3db", "question": "What was the four letter name of Thailand before 1949?", "answer": "Siam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015df0ffe83fe1f2a824b77", "question": "What two countries were involved in the Kargil War?", "answer": "India and Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb3571c2627b8fe95581be2", "question": "Chamorro is one of the official languages of which country?", "answer": "Guam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1bcaf6756c9b30ba14fe", "question": "Graham Kerr became famous under what nickname?", "answer": "The Galloping Gourmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339190", "question": "What are Tom and Jerry?", "answer": "A Cat and a Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11e", "question": "Who was the second US President to appear on the face of a US coin?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b589", "question": "What does a Turk call \"Turkish Delight\"?", "answer": "Lokum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51d2fff04d658268c9323", "question": "When the first Burger King Restaurant opened in 1954, how much did a hamburger cost?", "answer": "18 cents -- That is what David Edgerton charged for a hamburger when he opened the first Burger King Restaurant.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a5", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe525631bf59ab7d2e380f3", "question": "Which animal is pictured on the standard Canadian $2 coin?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af26", "question": "Which two armies fought in the Battle of Blood River?", "answer": "Boers and Zulus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbd4d3c00d154d7af00b8d4", "question": "In the music video \"Opposites Attract\", what is the name of the cat Paula Abdul dances with?", "answer": "MC Skat Kat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b8", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b014", "question": "The Orient Express is a train route between what two cities?", "answer": "Paris and Istanbul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd4", "question": "In 1991, who erected three thousand blue and yellow umbrellas on the coasts of California and Japan?", "answer": "Christo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2f", "question": "In what year did Atari introduce the arcade game \"Missile Command\"?", "answer": "1980", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a06", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Soundgarden?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b7", "question": "What did cowboys refer to as \"tonsil paint\"?", "answer": "Whisky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0d", "question": "How much does it cost to buy a railroad in the standard game of Monopoly?", "answer": "$200", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb67445dad637d903c883c", "question": "What country\u2019s land is mostly on an island, although most of its people live on a peninsula across the South China Sea?", "answer": "Malaysia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b08", "question": "What actor played the villain, Simon Gruber, in \"Die Hard with a Vengeance\"?", "answer": "Jeremy Irons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0a", "question": "What author created the character of The Continental Op?", "answer": "Dashiell Hammett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e38d1bef6c8a670a7957c58", "question": "As of 2020, who is the only US president to earn a PhD?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b6", "question": "Who played Steve Urkel in the TV show \"Family Matters\"?", "answer": "Jaleel White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ab", "question": "Tornadoes are columns of air that generally come into contact with what kind of clouds?", "answer": "Cumulonimbus cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931e", "question": "In the 2003 movie \"Finding Nemo\", what kind of animal does Marlin hitch a ride with?", "answer": "A turtle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb45f65ff7d326b622a86", "question": "What is the fear of glass known as?", "answer": "Nelophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad9", "question": "Edmonton is the capital of which Canadian province?", "answer": "Alberta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338911", "question": "What was the name of the cat in Walt Disney's movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339736", "question": "In the TV series \"Lost\", which airline's plane crashed?", "answer": "Oceanic Airlines", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c711", "question": "What unit of weight is equal to approximately .002 pounds?", "answer": "1 gram", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b562", "question": "What is the largest cultivated crop in the United States?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73e11eec85e375820b270", "question": "Which country do the Shetland Islands belong to?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523cc5736d4be723796b3a", "question": "Which city is home to the Blue Jays baseball team?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5707c73aa70ea0b70b2f", "question": "Which U.S. town is home to the world's largest rose bush?", "answer": "Tombstone, Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31b", "question": "Approximately how many kilometers are there in a nautical mile?", "answer": "1.85", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339465", "question": "Who wrote the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a2", "question": "What year was actress Diane Keaton born?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae94c1574a5ce6b56b824b", "question": "The cobnut is the fruit of what tree?", "answer": "Hazel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad80", "question": "In 1943, the \"One Thousand Mile War\" began when Japan invaded what set of islands?", "answer": "Aleutian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c91", "question": "What John Steinbeck novel is based on the biblical story of Cain & Abel?", "answer": "East of Eden", "category": "arts"}]